optimalblue.com 2019-11-12

# PRIVACY POLICY

                     OPTIMAL BLUE, LLC
                  PRIVACY POLICY
`
February 21, 2018         Page 1 of 12 Title

TABLE OF CONTENTS
     OUR COMMITMENT TO YOUR PRIVACY ................................................................. 1
     WHAT WE DO AND HOW WE RECEIVE INFORMATION ......................................... 2
     WEBSITE INFORMATION PRACTICES ........................................................................ 2
     GENERAL INFORMATION PRACTICES...................................................................... 4
     PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION PRACTICES ......................................... 5
     TECHNOLOGY PRACTICES ....................................................................................... 5
     INFORMATION SHARING PRACTICES ...................................................................... 7
     THIRD-PARTY USE OF COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES........... 8
     EMAIL COMMUNICATION PRACTICES .................................................................... 9
     SECURITY PRACTICES ................................................................................................ 9
     QUESTIONS ............................................................................................................... 10
February 21, 2018                                                                                              Privacy Policy

                                       Optimal Blue, LLC
                                   Privacy Policy (“Policy”)
    Optimal Blue, LLC, 5340 Legacy Drive, Building 2, 2nd Floor, Plano, TX 75024 which
    is referred to below as "Optimal Blue, LLC" “Optimal Blue” or "we" or "us" or "our."
    LAST UPDATED/EFFECTIVE DATE: February 21, 2018
OUR COMMITMENT TO YOUR PRIVACY
    At Optimal Blue, we respect and use commercially reasonable practices in order
    to protect the privacy of those who visit or use our Websites. When we collect
    information from you, we want you to know how it is used and protected.
    Because of the financial nature of our business which relates to the real estate
    market, our Websites, products or services are not designed to appeal to
    children under the age of thirteen (13) and are intended for use of adults over
    the age of eighteen (18). Therefore, we do not knowingly attempt to solicit,
    receive or collect any information from children, and children should not use our
    Websites, products or services at any time.
    This Policy describes Optimal Blue, LLC’s (together with its subsidiaries and
    affiliates, “Optimal Blue”) collection, processing, use and storage of data from
    customers of Optimal Blue products and services (and, where applicable, their
    customers) and from visitors to any of our corporate websites or social media
    pages, (collectively, “Websites”). Our Websites and Optimal Blue Services are
    referred to in this Policy, collectively, as our “Services.” Optimal Blue customers
    should also refer to their license agreement and other customer agreements
    including any Terms of Service, which may state additional terms governing their
    use of our Services. By visiting any of the Optimal Blue Websites, you are
    accepting the practices described in this Privacy Notice.
    This Policy applies to information we collect:
       •   On the Websites.
       •   In email, text, and other electronic messages between you and these
           Websites.
    It does not apply to information collected by:
       •   Us offline or through any other means, including on any other Websites
           operated by or for any third party; or
       •   Any third party, including through any application or content (including
           advertising) that may link to or be accessible from [or on] the Websites.
    February 21, 2018                             Page 1 of 10                  Privacy Policy

WHAT WE DO AND HOW WE RECEIVE INFORMATION
    We provide Services to our "Customers". In addition, we provide platforms that
    our Customers use to collect certain information which may include Personally
    Identifiable Information. In all such cases, we are acting only as agent for, or
    providing processing or other services to, our Customers. Our Customers are
    responsible for posting their privacy policies, providing notice and obtaining
    appropriate consents to collect information and to provide it to us as a third-
    party service provider. We recommend that you read and understand the
    privacy policies of any financial institution to whom you provide Personally
    Identifiable Information.
WEBSITE INFORMATION PRACTICES
    Optimal Blue collects information from visitors on the Websites and users of our
    Services in a variety of manners, and also obtains information from third parties in
    the course of providing our Services to our Customers. To maximize the value of
    our Services, we may request information from you when you visit our Websites.
    We collect several types of information from and about users of our Websites,
    including information:
      •   By which you may be personally identified, (see "Personally Identifiable
          Information Practices");
      •   That is about you but individually does not identify you, such as address or
          employment information.
      •   About your internet connection, the equipment you use to access our
          Websites and usage details.
    We collect this information:
      •   Directly from you when you provide it to us.
      •   Automatically as you navigate through the site. Information collected
          automatically may include usage details, IP addresses, and information
          collected through cookies, Web beacons, and other tracking technologies.
      •   From third parties, for example, financial institutions and loan originators.
    Here is a description of the information we collect and how it is used:
      •   Tools, Applications and Registration: If you as our Customer opts into
          receiving Services, we will ask you to register at the Website and supply
          other identifying and supporting information needed to process your
          request. By registering, you can save information for later review and
          update. When you register, you (i) select a member ID name (Username) by
          which we will know you, (ii) choose a password and (iii) provide us a valid
          email address. You use your unique Username and password to gain access
          to your information within our Services. When you log in or register, we
          collect your Username and password to ascertain your identity and display
          the proper Services to you. We use your contact information to provide you
    February 21, 2018                           Page 2 of 10                   Privacy Policy

     with alerts, information, and updates, which are a part of the Services. We
     may use your information, to send you communications and special offers
     on other products or Services offered by Optimal Blue. If you do not want to
     receive this information you may opt-out through the links provided in our
     email communications.
Optimal Blue or a third-party provider may also collect and/or store credit card
or ACH information you input or provide for billing purposes during the
subscription to our Services in order to enforce the terms of use, billing or other
contract-related activity. These companies are required to maintain such
information as confidential. Optimal Blue, however, is not responsible for the
unauthorized access, use, or disclosure of any non-public Personal Identification
Information or confidential information by a third party.
  •  Information You Provide in Sales Inquiries or Demonstration Requests: When
     you request information through the specific Website, we ask you to provide
     your name, title, company, address, email and telephone number.
  •  Registration Information: When you register to use one of the Services, we
     may collect certain information from you, including your name, email
     address, and other information that we use to contact you or provide
     Services to you.
  •  Borrower Information: In the course of delivering our hosted Services —we
     receive information about our Customers' mortgage borrowers or potential
     mortgage borrowers (which may include Personally Identifiable
     Information), which is provided to us by our Customers. Our Customers are
     responsible for posting their privacy policies, providing notice and obtaining
     appropriate consents to collect data from their borrowers or potential
     borrowers and to provide it to us as a third-party service provider.
  •  Transactional Information: Optimal Blue may also create transactional
     records of each of the transactions or other events occurring through our
     Services. This transactional information is generally collected for the purpose
     of loan document creation, origination, management, and distribution, to
     enable the Services we provide to our Customers (including the ability to
     document their determinations of qualification for loans or the interest rates
     to be applied to loans), and to enable our Customers to comply with
     various legal obligations.
  •  To Provide our Services: We may use the information that we collect (i) to
     operate, test, maintain, enhance and provide features of our Services; (ii) to
     provide additional Services or information that you request; and (iii) to
     provide support to Customers, users, and site visitors.
  •  To Improve, Analyze, and Personalize our Services: We may use the
     information that we collect (i) to understand and analyze usage trends and
February 21, 2018                          Page 3 of 10                    Privacy Policy

         preferences; (ii) to monitor and analyze the effectiveness of our Services; (iii)
         to improve our Services and develop new products, services, features, or
         functionality; (iv) to personalize our Services, and (v) to provide customized
         content and information.
      •  Aggregate, De-identified (Anonymized) Data: We may aggregate and de-
         identify (anonymize) data collected through our Services and may use it for
         purposes such as creating and publishing reports about the use of our
         Services, including users’ interests, usage patterns, and borrowing and loan
         origination trends.
GENERAL INFORMATION PRACTICES
      •  Mandatory and Optional Information: We identify what information is
         required to fulfill your request. If you chose not to provide mandatory
         information, we will not be able to provide you the service you are
         requesting.
      •  Service Alerts and Critical Notices: Although we respect and honor the
         privacy preferences you have expressed, we may need to contact you to
         inform you of specific changes that may impact your ability to use this
         service or for other critical non-marketing purposes, such as bug alerts. We
         may also contact you to respond to your specific requests, to clarify the
         order information you provided to us, or to notify you of upcoming
         subscription expiration dates.
      •  Links to other sites/Advertisers: Our Websites, products, and services may
         contain links to other sites, as well as advertisements from companies linking
         to their own sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the
         content of such sites. If you have any questions about how these other sites
         use your information, you should contact them directly.
      •  International Visitors: Our Services are hosted in the United States (U.S.) and
         are intended for use in connection with the U.S. real estate market only. If
         you choose to use them from regions of the world with laws governing data
         collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, then please note that you
         are transferring your information outside of those regions to the United
         States for storage and processing. By providing your information, you
         consent to any transfer and processing in accordance with this Policy.
      •  Changes to Our Policy: We reserve the right to modify or update this Policy
         at any time by posting modifications or updates on the Websites. The most
         current version of the policy will govern our use of your information and will
         always be available at www.optimalblue.com. By continuing to access or
         use the Services after those changes become effective, you agree to be
         bound by the revised Policy.
    February 21, 2018                            Page 4 of 10                 Privacy Policy

PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION PRACTICES
    Our Customers provide us information, which may include Personally Identifiable
    Information of their mortgage customers/consumers and potential mortgage
    borrowers, so that we may provide our Services to our customers. Personally
    Identifiable Information (PII) is any information that is not publicly available about
    an individual that can be used directly, or in connection with other data, to
    identify, contact or locate that person.
    We employ industry recognized security safeguards to help protect any
    Personally Identifiable Information and sensitive information that may be
    collected, stored, or provided by our Customers. We safeguard Personally
    Identifiable Information and sensitive information stored on the Website's servers
    from unauthorized access using industry standard computer security protocols,
    such as firewalls or encryption and we may use other commercially reasonable
    accepted security procedures and practices. All employees must review and
    execute a Non-Disclosure Agreement and participate in ongoing security
    practices training. Additional privacy safeguard practices may include limiting
    access to sensitive information, enforcing strict password protocols for all
    employees, and unique usernames and passwords are required to access, use,
    or view contracted Services. We utilize internal and external resources to review
    and conduct testing as to the adequacy of our security measures on a regular
    basis.
      •   Aggregate, De-Identified (Anonymized) Form: We may make certain
          aggregated, de-identified (anonymized) non-personal information
          available to third parties or Customers for various purposes, including (i) for
          compliance with various reporting obligations; (ii) for business or marketing
          purposes; or (iii) to assist such parties in understanding our users’ interests,
          usage patterns, and borrowing and loan origination trends.
      •   Change of Control: Your information, including Personally Identifiable
          Information may be transferred, disclosed, or otherwise transferred to an
          acquirer, successor, or assignee in connection with a sale of assets, merger,
          transfer, exchange, debt financing, or other disposition (whether of assets,
          stock or otherwise) or in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or
          receivership in which information is transferred to one or more third parties
          of all or a portion of Optimal Blue, LLC.
TECHNOLOGY PRACTICES
    The information we collect may include personal information or we may
    maintain it or associate it with personal information we collect in other ways or
    receive from third parties. Here is how and why we may use some common
    technologies to help manage our Services, including our Websites:
      •   Cookies and Other Technologies: A "cookie" is a small piece of information
          that our Websites may provide to your browser while you are at our sites. We
    February 21, 2018                             Page 5 of 10                   Privacy Policy

     collect certain information through the use of “cookies” and other tracking
     technologies. We may use session cookies, persistent cookies, order tracking
     cookies, and other tracking technologies to better understand how you
     interact with our Services, to monitor usage by our users and web traffic
     routing on our Services, and to improve and personalize our Services. Most
     Internet browsers automatically accept cookies. You can instruct your
     browser to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting
     cookies from the websites you visit. We may also use web beacons, which
     are transparent graphic images on a webpage or within the body of one of
     our marketing emails, to allow us to measure visitor actions and assess the
     effectiveness of our Services or email marketing campaigns. For example,
     we use web beacons in our email marketing to track instances where a user
     clicks through a link in the email.
  •  Website Usage Data: Our Websites tracks or collects standard technical
     usage data, including, for example, your internet protocol (IP) address, your
     browser type and version, Internet Service Providers (ISPs), which pages you
     view, which page, if any, linked you to our site, and which link, if any, you
     follow off of our site. We use this data in the aggregate and on an individual
     level to better understand specific Website activity to improve our site
     offerings, to reconstruct activity from a session or by a user, for
     troubleshooting and issue resolution purposes. We may also use this data to
     provide you a more personalized Website experience, assistance with
     technical support questions, and to send you special offers, product and
     service updates, or other promotional materials that are relevant and
     tailored to your interests. Optimal Blue may also employ third party service
     providers to help us collect and understand our Website’s usage data.
We give you the opportunity to control the use of your personal information for
purposes other than to fulfill your request. For example, on occasion we may use
your contact information to send you promotional communications about
Optimal Blue products. If you do not wish to receive such communications and
wish to be removed, you may send an email notating your request to
clientservices@optimalblue.com.
  •  Google Analytics: We also may use these technologies to collect
     information about your online activities over time and across third-party
     websites or other online services (behavioral tracking). Our Sites use Google
     Analytics, a web analytic service provided by Google, Inc. Google
     Analytics uses JavaScript ad cookies to help us analyze how visitors use the
     Optimal Blue Websites. For more information on Google Analytics cookies,
     visit www.google.com/policies. Google provides some additional privacy
     options relating to Google Analytics, described at
     www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners. For information on how you
     can opt out of behavioral tracking or to opt-out of being tracked by
     Google Analytics across all websites visit
February 21, 2018                           Page 6 of 10                  Privacy Policy

            http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout. This allows you to download
            and install a Google Analytics cookie-free web browser.
INFORMATION SHARING PRACTICES
    Optimal Blue may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide to
    fulfill the purpose for which you provide it, for any other purpose disclosed by us
    when you provide the information and with your consent. We may also disclose
    information as described in this Policy and may share, transfer, or disclose your
    information if you consent to us doing so, as well as in the following
    circumstances:
      •     To Our Customers: We may disclose aggregated information about our
            users, and information that does not identify any individual, without
            restriction. Transactional information collected through our Services may be
            available to Customer Account Managers or other Optimal Blue employees
            required by their role, and may be shared with loan originators or other
            Optimal Blue Customers. Optimal Blue Customers may use certain
            information they collect through Optimal Blue platforms (such as the
            Optimal Blue Consumer Direct and Point of Sale Services) for marketing,
            promotional communications, or as participants to the subscribers and
            licensees of our services.
      •     To Service Providers: In some cases, we will employ or use service providers
            such as consultants, temporary workers, and third-party software
            developers, or other third-party providers to provide website services or
            hosting, maintenance, operations, marketing, and other services as needed
            to complete a business process or provide a service on our behalf. For
            example, we may use service providers to enhance our website’s
            technology, deliver products, or to send emails on our behalf. These third
            parties may have access to or process your information as part of providing
            those services for us. Generally, we limit the information provided to these
            service providers to that which is reasonably necessary for them to perform
            their functions, and we require them to agree in writing to maintain the
            confidentiality of such information. Third party service providers are strictly
            prohibited from using our Customer’s Confidential Information for purposes
            other than to act on our behalf.
      •     Legal Disclosures: In some cases, we may disclose certain information to
            comply with a legal process, such as a court order, subpoena, search
            warrant, or law enforcement request when (a) we believe that disclosure is
            reasonably necessary to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal
            process, regulator or governmental request, (b) to enforce our agreements,
            policies and terms of service, (c) to protect the security or integrity of our
            Services, including our Websites, (d) to protect the property, business rights,
            and safety of Optimal Blue, our users, or the public from harm or illegal
            activities, (e) to respond to an emergency which we believe in good faith
            requires us to disclose information to assist in preventing the death or serious
    February 21, 2018                             Page 7 of 10                    Privacy Policy

          bodily injury of any person, or (f) to investigate and defend ourselves
          against any claims or allegations.
       •  Within the Optimal Blue Family: Within Optimal Blue, our parent company
          and other affiliated partners we may exchange our Customer information.
       •  To a Buyer or Other Successor: In the event of a merger, divestiture,
          restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or
          all of Company’s assets, whether as a going concern or as part of
          bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which personal information
          held by Company about our Website’s users is among the assets
          transferred.
       •  To Third Parties: To market their products or services to you if you have
          consented to or not opted out of these disclosures. We contractually
          require these third parties to keep personal information confidential and use
          it only for the purposes for which we disclose it to them.
     We may also disclose personal information:
       •  To enforce or apply our terms of use in any executed Optimal Blue Terms of
          Service, Agreements, Amendments or Addendums thereto including for
          billing and collection purposes.
       •  If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights,
          property, or safety of the Company, our customers, or others. Disclosure
          may include exchanging information with other companies and
          organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.
THIRD-PARTY USE OF COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES
     Some content or applications, including advertisements, on the Websites are
     served by third-parties, including advertisers, ad networks and servers, content
     providers, and application providers. While we generally do not allow them to
     collect personally identifiable tracking information from consumers, these third
     parties may use cookies (alone or in conjunction with web beacons or other
     tracking technologies) to collect information about you when you use our
     websites. The information they collect may be associated with your personal
     information or they may collect information, including personal information,
     about your online activities over time and across different websites and other
     online services. They may use this information to provide you with interest-based
     (behavioral) advertising or other targeted content.
     We do not control these third parties’ tracking technologies or how they may be
     used nor are we responsible for those third parties’ practices. If you have any
     questions about an advertisement or other targeted content, you should
     contact the responsible provider directly. We encourage you to visit the third
     parties’ websites to learn about their privacy practices. For information about
     February 21, 2018                            Page 8 of 10                   Privacy Policy

    how you can opt out of receiving targeted advertising from many providers, see
    Technology Practices section.
EMAIL COMMUNICATION PRACTICES
    Our Anti-Spam practices tolerate only permission-based email. You may choose
    to opt-out or select your email preferences when you sign-up for our email lists.
    You always have the opportunity to opt-out or change preferences by following
    a link in the footer of all non-transactional email messages sent by us via email. In
    addition, anyone receiving emails from us on behalf of our Customers always has
    the opportunity to opt-out of email messages from such Customer by using the
    opt-out link included in the link in the footer of the message.
      •   Email Message Formatting: We may use your email address or other
          information we collect to contact you for administrative purposes such as
          customer service or to send communications, including marketing or
          promotional communications relating to our Services. When sending you
          email we may use an image called a single-pixel GIF, that allows us to (i)
          format messages that best align with your computer's capabilities, and (ii)
          determine whether you have opened an HTML email. When you click on a
          link within an email message, you will first pass through our server, and then
          are redirected onto the Internet. We use this data on an aggregate level to
          evaluate response rates to our email messages and to determine which
          links are most useful to our client base. Generally, you have the ability to opt
          out of receiving promotional communications as described below.
SECURITY PRACTICES
    Optimal Blue has commercially reasonable industry standard physical,
    administrative and technical measures in place to maintain the security,
    confidentiality and integrity of the information gathered through the Websites,
    and to help protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of such information.
    For example, Optimal Blue generally uses Transport Layer Security (TLS) and uses
    server authentication when you connect to the Optimal Blue Services. While we
    take reasonable steps to protect information and data against security breaches
    and unauthorized access, no data transmission over the Internet can be
    guaranteed to be totally secure and therefore we cannot guarantee or warrant
    the security of any information you send to us.
    All data sent to Optimal Blue through its Websites is reasonably protected with
    technology that enables encryption of your data using methods such as:
      •   Secure Socket Layer (SSL): The Optimal Blue Web server supports the Secure
          Socket Layer (SSL) transaction protocol. The purpose of this encryption
          protocol is to keep confidential the information passed back and forth
          between a Web server and its users.
    February 21, 2018                           Page 9 of 10                   Privacy Policy

       •  128-Bit Domestic Grade Strong Encryption: Optimal Blue uses a minimum of
          128-Bit Domestic Grade Strong Encryption and will increase this standard as
          commercially available enhancements become widely supported on the
          Internet.
QUESTIONS
    If you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding the Optimal Blue
    Security and Privacy Policy, our information practices or other aspects of the
    security or privacy on our Websites, please contact us via email at
    clientservices@optimalblue.com or by writing to us at Optimal Blue, LLC, Attn:
    Legal Department, 5340 Legacy Drive, Building 2, 2nd Floor, Plano, TX 75024.
    February 21, 2018                         Page 10 of 10                 Privacy Policy
